Alex Loughlin

Front End Web Developer London

I am a front end web developer with a keen eye for design and thoughtful UI and UX. I enjoy the unique role front end web work has in solving usability problems and achieving clients desired aims for their sites. I feel that good front-end development is the key differentiating point between successful and unsuccessful websites.

My most recent role has seen me be the sole, full-time developer for a brand and marketing agency based in London. This role has allowed me to learn and grow more so than any other job I have had. During my time at Drew, I have done much more than front end work, having delivered full sites such as Blakademik and Rash&Rash. I have also had direct and regular contact with clients, being their main point of contact for many of them. This experience has allowed me to gain the necessary skills to work well within a team and also handle and deliver for clients directly.

I personally love the challenge of designing beautiful and easy to use UIs. Then taking those designs and translating them into great products. I am looking forward to working with a team of people who are also enthusiastic about tackling the main varied and new problems facing web and application design. To see examples of my work please visit my personal website at www.alexloughlin.com

Work Experience

Drew London

Front End Web Developer | Aug 2018 - Current

My time at Drew London has been a fulfilling and ever-challenging role, spanning everything from handling client relations to delivering fully equipped WordPress websites. I have managed and help deliver over 25 sites while at Drew, managing current clients Drew have had for years and brand new clients. The breadth of Drew's client portfolio meant I have experience working with companies as large as M&G Investments, to luxury shoe brands and everything in between. As a small team of less than 8 staff, we can deliver websites serving thousands of people in a quick time frame hopefully exceeding the client's expectations.

Every website we build is a custom Wordpress site including a custom theme. We do this because having tried to use off-the-shelf themes, this rarely saves you time. As a client's wants and expectations will move passed a theme very quickly. This results in more work trying to fit it to what the client wants whereas if we start from custom, we only build what we need. This results in a much faster website, with less unused code and bloat. A custom approach also allows us more flexibility and creativity in our website designs as we are only restricted by what we think we can achieve and nothing else. You can see this for yourself in the beautiful and thoughtfully designed websites I have delivered while at Drew such as It's All Blakademik, Rash&Rash and SRG Movement. I have developed good skills in both PHP and Liquid having worked with both in-depth while at Drew. My time there has also expanded my knowledge of deployment methods for websites. I have maintained a Capistranio based development method and helped implement a CircleCi method for more advanced sites going forward.

My time at Drew has also allowed me to improve my skills in client relations. As the only full-time developer at Drew, it is necessary that I am involved in client meetings from the start, so that we can give them a realistic quote and timeframe. I will then be involved in communicating directly with the client from then on, as I feel it is good for clients to hear from a developer as well as a project manager. The extra technical knowledge can help reassure a client and calm any fears or worries they may have before or during a project. At Drew, I will speak to clients nearly every day. Meaning I now feel very comfortable in a client-facing role and would like to expand on it going forward.

- It's All Blakademik
- Rash&Rash
- SRG Movement
- MTMP
- <u>Bond Vigilantes</u> one example of the seven sites I helped manage for M&G Investments.

Govnet Communications

Front End Web Developer | Jan 2017 – Aug 2018

My role at Govnet has been an interesting and varied one as I have been working on a very small four-person in-house team. Even though it is a small team, we are responsible for over 40 event sites including expos which have an attendance of nearly 5000 people. This scale means we have to liaise with 6 different divisions split across the company all with separate and competing events and timescales.

Every event site is a custom Wordpress build, never using any off the shelf themes. This allows us the complete flexibility to build interesting and effective elements for every show. Just before I left we had were nearly finished the large task of implementing a brand new CMS and CRM system for the entire company portfolio called Affino.

Vitamin London

Junior Front End Web Developer | Jul 2016 - Dec 2016

My time at Vitamin London was spent mainly being the sole front-end developer on a variety of projects. These projects were mostly e-commerce sites using Shopify and some Wordpress based projects. One example project is Van Loon Sport, a new and high-end ski-wear brand based out of London. Their website, vanloonsport.com, uses Shopify and a basic theme. I was responsible for the main functionality and set up of the website, making sure the structure and user journey matched the Client's exacting expectations. As Vitamin London is a small design agency, I was given many chances to interact very closely with clients. Making sure their projects got to the exact place the Client envisioned them.

Education

University of Westminster

First Class Honours - Multimedia Computing (BSc) | Sep 2013 - Jun 2016

My university degree allowed me to try a wide and varied range of topics from the computer science world. During my three years, I was exposed to everything from Java and Unix, web design to animation and even cybersecurity. This allowed me to learn which elements of the industry I really enjoyed. So that when it came to my third year I was able to specialise. My specific interests ended up being Responsive Web Design and Mobile Design

(Web and native applications). I enjoyed the challenge of designing and testing well thought out user interfaces and experiences. Then bring them to life through programming languages such as Swift, HTML5 and Javascript specifically.

Skills

HTML 5

CSS (including preprocessors such as SASS)

Javascript (jQuery and Vanilla)

Static Site Generators - Jekyll

PHP

Responsive Design for Web

Gulp

CircleCi

Liquid

Capistrano

Swift

Grid-based systems for scalable Web Design

Content Management Systems (Wordpress + Affino + Shopify)

Project Management Software - Float, Trello

Adobe CC Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop + Indesign)

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email: <u>aloughlin711@gmail.com</u>

Telephone: 447590814386

Website: http://alexloughlin.com